MALCOLM C. A. WHITE

50 Oakland St., Floor 2, Medford, MA 02155 (339) 221-7195 \$\phi\$ malcolm.white@usc.edu

PERSONAL STATEMENT

My research interests span the spectrum of computational methods in seismology—from observational problems, like elastic-wave-phase detection; to forward problems, like modeling propagating wavefronts; and inverse problems, like locating earthquakes—and how to synthesize these to investigate structural and mechanical properties of the Earth's subsurface.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Python, C/C++, Fortran, Mathematica, Bash Computer Languages

Software & Tools Antelope, GnuCash, LATEX, Excel

EDUCATION

University of Southern California

August 2016 - Present PhD in Earth Sciences Overall GPA: 3.45/4.0

Department of Earth Sciences

Carleton University September 2007 - May 2013

Honours BSc in Computational Geophysics Department of Earth Sciences

EMPLOYMENT

August 2013 - June 2016 Scripps Institution of Oceanography

Seismic Analyst La Jolla, California, USA

Pacific Geoscience Center June 2012 - June 2013

Research Assistant Sidney, British Columbia, Canada

Pacific Geoscience Center May 2011 - August 2011

Research Assistant Sidney, British Columbia, Canada

Geological Survey of Canada May 2010 - August 2010

Research Assistant Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

TEACHING

2018 The Nature of Scientific Inquiry

Examination of the scientific process: what constitutes science; evolution of ideas about the nature of space, time, matter, and complexity; paradigm shifts in the biological and earth sciences. Lecture, 3 hours; laboratory, 2 hours.

2017 Earthquakes

Causes of earthquakes and nature of large faults; earthquake hazard and risk; world's great earthquakes; understanding the Richter scale. Lecture, 3 hours; laboratory, 2 hours.

The Nature of Scientific Inquiry

Examination of the scientific process: what constitutes science; evolution of ideas about the nature of space, time, matter, and complexity; paradigm shifts in the biological and earth sciences. Lecture, 3 hours; laboratory, 2 hours.

American Geophysical Union Seismological Society of America

PUBLICATIONS

- White, M. C. A., Ben-Zion, Y., & Vernon, F. L. (2019). A Detailed Earthquake Catalog for the San Jacinto Fault-Zone Region in Southern California. *Journal of Geophysical Research:* Solid Earth, 124, 6908–6930. https://doi.org/10.1029/2019JB017641
- Burdick, S., Vernon, F. L., Martynov, V., Eakins, J., Cox, T., Tytell, J., ... van der Hilst, R. D. (2017). Model Update May 2016: Upper-Mantle Heterogeneity beneath North America from Travel-Time Tomography with Global and USArray Data. Seismological Research Letters, 88(2A), 319–325. https://doi.org/10.1785/0220160186
- Ross, Z. E., Ben-Zion, Y., White, M. C., & Vernon, F. L. (2016). Analysis of earthquake body wave spectra for potency and magnitude values: implications for magnitude scaling relations. Geophysical Journal International, 207(2), 1158–1164. https://doi.org/10.1093/gji/ggw327
 - Ross, Z. E., White, M. C., Vernon, F. L., & Ben-Zion, Y. (2016). An Improved Algorithm for Real-Time S -Wave Picking with Application to the (Augmented) ANZA Network in Southern California. *Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America*, 106(5), 2013–2022. https://doi.org/10.1785/0120150230
- Ben-Zion, Y., Vernon, F. L., Ozakin, Y., Zigone, D., Ross, Z. E., Meng, H., ... Barklage, M. (2015). Basic data features and results from a spatially dense seismic array on the San Jacinto fault zone. Geophysical Journal International, 202(1), 370–380. https://doi.org/10.1093/gji/ggv142
- Astiz, L., Eakins, J. A., Martynov, V. G., Cox, T. A., Tytell, J., Reyes, J. C., ... Vernon, F. L. (2014). The Array Network Facility Seismic Bulletin: Products and an Unbiased View of United States Seismicity. Seismological Research Letters, 85(3), 576–593. https://doi.org/10.1785/0220130141